<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>stdlib on Ferret</title>
    <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/</link>
    <description>Recent content in stdlib on Ferret</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>arrays</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/arrays/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/arrays/</guid>
      <description>FIRST Source
First returns a first element from a given array.
          Argument Type Description   arr Array Target array.    Returns Value First element in a given array.
 REMOVE_VALUE Source
RemoveValue returns a new array with removed all occurrences of value in a given array. Optionally with a limit to the number of removals.
          Argument Type Description   array Array Source array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>collections</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/collections/</guid>
      <description>LENGTH Source
Length returns the length of a measurable value.
          Argument Type Description   value String Array Object Binary The value to measure.    Returns Int Returns the length of the value.
 REVERSE Source
Reverse returns the reverse of a given string or array value.
          Argument Type Description   text String Array The string or array to reverse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>datetime</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/datetime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/datetime/</guid>
      <description>DATE_DAYOFWEEK Source
DateDayOfWeek returns number of the weekday from the date. Sunday is the 0th day of week.
          Argument Type Description   date DateTime Source datetime.    Returns Int Return number of the weekday.
 DATE_YEAR Source
DateYear returns the year extracted from the given date.
          Argument Type Description   date DateTime Source datetime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>html</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/html/</guid>
      <description>ELEMENT_EXISTS Source
ELEMENT_EXISTS returns a boolean value indicating whether there is an element matched by selector.
          Argument Type Description   docOrEl HTMLDocument HTMLNode Parent document or element.   selector String Css selector.    Returns Boolean A boolean value indicating whether there is an element matched by selector.
 BLUR Source
BLUR Calls blur on the element.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>io/fs</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/io-fs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/io-fs/</guid>
      <description>READ Source
Read reads from a given file.
          Argument Type Description   path String Path to file to read from.    Returns Binary The read file in binary format.
 WRITE Source
Write writes the given data into the file.
          Argument Type Description   path String Path to file to write into.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>io/net/http</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/io-net-http/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/io-net-http/</guid>
      <description>POST Source
POST makes a POST request.
          Argument Type Description   params (Object) - request parameters. * url (String) - Target url * body Binary Post data * headers (object) optional - http headers    Returns None
 DELETE Source
DELETE makes a HTTP DELETE request.
          Argument Type Description   params (Object) - request parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>math</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/math/</guid>
      <description>MIN Source
Min returns the smallest (arithmetic mean) of the values in array.
          Argument Type Description   array Array Array of numbers.    Returns Float The smallest of the values in array.
 RADIANS Source
Radians returns the angle converted from degrees to radians.
          Argument Type Description   number Float Int The input number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>objects</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/objects/</guid>
      <description>KEYS Source
Keys returns string array of object&amp;rsquo;s keys
          Argument Type Description   obj Object The object whose keys you want to extract   sort Boolean, optional If sort is true, then the returned keys will be sorted.    Returns Array of String Array that contains object keys.
 HAS Source
Has returns the value stored by the given key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>path</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/path/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/path/</guid>
      <description>MATCH Source
Match reports whether name matches the pattern.
          Argument Type Description   pattern String The pattern.   name String The name.    Returns Boolean True if the name mathes the pattern.
 BASE Source
Base returns the last component of the path. or the path itself if it does not contain any directory separators.
          Argument Type Description   path String The path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>strings</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/strings/</guid>
      <description>LIKE Source
Like checks whether the pattern search is contained in the string text, using wildcard matching.
          Argument Type Description   text String The string to search in.   search String A search pattern that can contain the wildcard characters.   caseInsensitive Boolean If set to true, the matching will be case-insensitive. the default is false.    Returns Boolean Returns true if the pattern is contained in text, and false otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>types</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/types/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/types/</guid>
      <description>IS_BINARY Source
IsBinary checks whether value is a binary value.
          Argument Type Description   value Value Input value of arbitrary type.    Returns Boolean Returns true if value is binary, otherwise false.
 TO_ARRAY Source
toArray takes an input value of any type and convert it into an array value.
          Argument Type Description   value Value Input value of arbitrary type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>utils</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/utils/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/utils/</guid>
      <description>WAIT Source
Wait pauses the execution for a given period.
          Argument Type Description   timeout Float Int Number value which indicates for how long to stop an execution.    Returns None
 PRINT Source
Print writes messages into the system log.
          Argument Type Description    Returns None Returns none</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>