<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>stdlib on Ferret</title>
    <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/</link>
    <description>Recent content in stdlib on Ferret</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>arrays</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/arrays/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/arrays/</guid>
      <description>APPEND Source
APPEND appends a new item to an array and returns a new array with a given element. If uniqueOnly is set to true, then will add the item only if it&amp;rsquo;s unique.
Argument Type Default value Description arr Any[] Target array. item Any Target value to add. Returns Any[] New array.
FIRST Source
FIRST returns a first element from a given array.
Argument Type Default value Description arr Any[] Target array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>collections</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/collections/</guid>
      <description>INCLUDES Source
INCLUDES checks whether a container includes a given value.
Argument Type Default value Description haystack String Any[] Object Iterable The value container. needle Any The target value to assert. Returns Boolean A boolean value that indicates whether a container contains a given value.
LENGTH Source
LENGTH returns the length of a measurable value.
Argument Type Default value Description value Measurable The value to measure. Returns Int The length of the value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>datetime</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/datetime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/datetime/</guid>
      <description>DATE Source
DATE converts RFC3339 date time string to DateTime object.
Argument Type Default value Description time String String in rfc3339 format. Returns DateTime New datetime object derived from timestring.
DATE_ADD Source
DATE_ADD adds amount given in unit to date. The following units are available: * y, year, year * m, month, months * w, week, weeks * d, day, days * h, hour, hours * i, minute, minutes * s, second, seconds * f, millisecond, milliseconds</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>html</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/html/</guid>
      <description>ATTR_GET Source
ATTR_GET gets single or more attribute(s) of a given element.
Argument Type Default value Description node HTMLPage HTMLDocument HTMLElement Target node. attrNames String, repeated Attribute name(s). Returns Object Key-value pairs of attribute values.
ATTR_QUERY Source
ATTR_QUERY finds a single or more attribute(s) by an query selector.
Argument Type Default value Description node HTMLPage HTMLDocument HTMLElement Target node. selector String Query selector. attrName String, repeated Attr name(s). Returns Object Key-value pairs of attribute values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>io/fs</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/io-fs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/io-fs/</guid>
      <description>IO::FS::READ Source
READ reads from a given file.
Argument Type Default value Description path String Path to file to read from. Returns Binary File content in binary format.
IO::FS::WRITE Source
WRITE writes the given data into the file.
Argument Type Default value Description path String File path to write into. data Binary Data to write. params Object Additional parameters: params.mode String Write (default): will create a file if the specified file does not exist Returns None</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>io/net/http</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/io-net-http/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/io-net-http/</guid>
      <description>IO::NET::HTTP::DELETE Source
DELETE makes a HTTP DELETE request.
Argument Type Default value Description params Object Request parameters. params.url String Target url params.body Binary Request data params.headers Object Http headers Returns Binary Response in binary format
IO::NET::HTTP::DO Source
REQUEST makes a HTTP request.
Argument Type Default value Description params Object Request parameters. params.method String Http method params.url String Target url params.body Binary Request data params.headers Object Http headers Returns Binary Response in binary format</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>math</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/math/</guid>
      <description>ABS Source
ABS returns the absolute value of a given number.
Argument Type Default value Description number Int Float Input number. Returns Float The absolute value of a given number.
ACOS Source
ACOS returns the arccosine, in radians, of a given number.
Argument Type Default value Description number Int Float Input number. Returns Float The arccosine, in radians, of a given number.
ASIN Source
ASIN returns the arcsine, in radians, of a given number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>objects</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/objects/</guid>
      <description>HAS Source
HAS returns the value stored by the given key.
Argument Type Default value Description key String The key name string. Returns Boolean True if the key exists else false.
KEEP_KEYS Source
KEEP_KEYS returns a new object with only given keys.
Argument Type Default value Description obj Object Source object. keys String, repeated Keys that need to be kept. Returns Object New object with only given keys.
KEYS Source</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>path</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/path/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/path/</guid>
      <description>PATH::BASE Source
BASE returns the last component of the path or the path itself if it does not contain any directory separators.
Argument Type Default value Description path String The path. Returns String The last component of the path.
PATH::CLEAN Source
CLEAN returns the shortest path name equivalent to path.
Argument Type Default value Description path String The path. Returns String The shortest path name equivalent to path
PATH::DIR Source</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>strings</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/strings/</guid>
      <description>CONCAT Source
CONCAT concatenates one or more instances of String, or an Array.
Argument Type Default value Description src String, repeated String[] The source string / array. Returns String A string value.
CONCAT_SEPARATOR Source
CONCAT_SEPARATOR concatenates one or more instances of String, or an Array with a given separator.
Argument Type Default value Description separator String The separator string. src String, repeated String[] The source string / array. Returns String Concatenated string.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>testing</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/testing/</guid>
      <description>T::ARRAY Source
ARRAY asserts that value is a array type.
Argument Type Default value Description actual Any Value to test. message String Message to display on error. Returns None
T::BINARY Source
BINARY asserts that value is a binary type.
Argument Type Default value Description actual Any Value to test. message String Message to display on error. Returns None
T::DATETIME Source
DATETIME asserts that value is a datetime type.
Argument Type Default value Description actual Any Value to test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>types</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/types/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/types/</guid>
      <description>IS_ARRAY Source
IS_ARRAY checks whether value is an array value.
Argument Type Default value Description value Any Input value of arbitrary type. Returns Boolean Returns true if value is array, otherwise false.
IS_BINARY Source
IS_BINARY checks whether value is a binary value.
Argument Type Default value Description value Any Input value of arbitrary type. Returns Boolean Returns true if value is binary, otherwise false.
IS_BOOL Source
IS_BOOL checks whether value is a boolean value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>utils</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/utils/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/stdlib/utils/</guid>
      <description>PRINT Source
PRINT writes messages into the system log.
Argument Type Default value Description message Value, repeated Print message. Returns None
WAIT Source
WAIT pauses the execution for a given period.
Argument Type Default value Description timeout Int Float Number value which indicates for how long to stop an execution. Returns None</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
