<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Ferret</title>
    <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Ferret</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.montferret.dev/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ferret v0.16.0</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.16.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.16.0/</guid>
      <description>Hello friends,
We hope everyone is healthy, happy, and ready for winter :)
Our team is back from the break and excited to announce a new Ferret release!
Ferret v0.16.0 is here and now it&amp;rsquo;s more stable, flexible, and faster!
As always, CLI can be found here and the runtime itself here.
Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and see what we&amp;rsquo;ve got!
What&amp;rsquo;s new In this release, besides internal optimizations, we&amp;rsquo;ve focused on new language syntax and order to</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferret v0.15.0</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.15.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.15.0/</guid>
      <description>Hello friends,
Ferret v0.15.0 is out. This release is more focused on bug fixes and API improvements.
Since the runtime and CLI have been splitted into 2 different repositories, you can find CLI binaries here which was upgraded to v1.1.0.
What&amp;rsquo;s added Support of document charset in HTTP driver If your target page does not contain information if its content encoding and it is other than utf-8, you can help http driver to properly convert the page content into utf-8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say &#39;Hello&#39; to new CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/say-hello-to-new-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/say-hello-to-new-cli/</guid>
      <description>Hello fellas,
We are happy to announce that we finally have a brand new Ferret CLI!
 As the project grows, it became clear that we need to separate Ferret Runtime and CLI, to let the projects evolve on their own.
The separation allowed us to review what we need from CLI and rebuild it from the ground up.
Thus, let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and see what&amp;rsquo;s in there.
Get started First of all, we need to install it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferret v0.14.0</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.14.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.14.0/</guid>
      <description>Hello friends,
Belated happy new 2021 year! Hope things will be better and we can finally get back to normal life.
Meanwhile, in between of work, personal lives and anxiety, we&amp;rsquo;ve managed to bring you some great features with a new release of Ferret - Ferret v0.14.0.
This release contains some syntax updates, DOM API fixes and extra flexibility. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in!
What&amp;rsquo;s added Support of History API Before v0.14.0, Page object from the CDP driver, would only return the url that was set during full page load or redirect but ignored all in page navigation using History API (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferret v0.13.0</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.13.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.13.0/</guid>
      <description>Hello friends,
We are excited to announce a new Ferret release - Ferret v0.13.0.
This release brings new syntax, DOM API updates and some bug fixes. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in!
What&amp;rsquo;s added While loop Finally! While loops have landed FQL!
Ferret query language inherently lacked while loops due to its origin from ArangoDB query language. But over time, it&amp;rsquo;s become obvious that this kind of looping is essential for data scraping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say &#39;Hello&#39; to Lab</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/say-hello-to-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/say-hello-to-lab/</guid>
      <description>Hello friends,
Our team is excited to announce a new tool in our ecosystem - The Lab!
The Lab is a test runner for Ferret that helps you to test how your scripts retrieve data or validate web UI.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see how it works!
Get started The Lab can be installed either by downloading a binary or pulling a Docker image:
$ docker pull montferret/lab If you are macOS/Linux user, you can install the latest binary with the shell script:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferret v0.12.0</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.12.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.12.0/</guid>
      <description>Hello fellow miners,
We are happy to announce a new Ferret release - Ferret v0.12.0.
This release has a new useful module in the standard library - testing!
Let&amp;rsquo;s dig in. The full changelog you can find here.
 What&amp;rsquo;s added Assertion library A new T namespace has been added to the standard library that provides some helpful methods for making assertions. The functions can be used to test UI, validate data and ensure the correctnes of a script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferret v0.11.1</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.11.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.11.1/</guid>
      <description>Hello fellow miners,
Ferret v0.11.1 has been released with a hotfix that solves an error in some functions that do screen positioning using scrolling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferret v0.11.0</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.11.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.11.0/</guid>
      <description>Hello fellow miners,
Today, we are living in unprecedented times. There are almost 5 million people infected by COVID-19 and thousands die every day in the world.
During this time, the highest priority is to stay safe and healthy, take care of family.
 Ferret team has been locked down in their homes with their families as everyone around the globe, but still has managed to make new Ferret v0.11.0 release!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New release strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/new-release-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/new-release-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Working on an open source project while you have a full time job sometimes is challenging. Especially, when you try to make every release full of new features and bug fixes.
Recent Ferret releases have showed, that trying to bring many features at one time is very time consuming and frustrating for end users. Therefore, our team has decided to change our release strategy.
In order to ship new releases more frequently, we are going to decrease amount of features and bug fixes per release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferret v0.10.0</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.10.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.10.0/</guid>
      <description>Hello fellow miners, Ferret v0.10.0 has been finally released!
It&amp;rsquo;s been long and busy 6 months since the last release and many of you might thought that the project got abandoned. We assure you it&amp;rsquo;s not! But sometimes life happens and slows you down.
But we are back and ready to rock!
This release has many great features and improvements thank to all our contributors. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the most important ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferret v0.9</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.9/</guid>
      <description>Hello fellow miners, Ferret v0.9 has been released!
In this release, we mostly focused on bug fixes and filling gaps in user interaction functionality.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see what we&amp;rsquo;ve got.
What&amp;rsquo;s added Clearing input values Since early versions, Ferret has INPUT HTML function that allowed to type any value to input HTML element. This works by appending the function parameter to any pre-existing &amp;lt;input&amp;gt; value. While it works fine in many cases, there are some scenarios when a target input field has a preset value which needs to be erased.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferret v0.8.2</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.8.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.8.2/</guid>
      <description>Another portion of hot fixes has arrived!
v0.8.2 release brings some critical fixes.
Scrolling position is not centered In 0.8, we introduced a new behavior for all user interactions. Before any actions like clicking ot typing, we scroll into a target element making it visible in a viewport. But the logic behind it, positioned elements on the top of the viewport, which led to some issues on some websites due to their markup - the elements were still invisible because they were under other elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferret v0.8.1</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.8.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.8.1/</guid>
      <description>With all big features, come small bugs. :)
With this new v0.8.1 release we are providing hot fixes for some of these small ones.
Broken CLICK function In 0.7 CLICK and CLICK_ALL functions were doing a check before clicking and was returning a boolean value indicating whether a target element was clicked. In 0.8 this logic got broken due to internal refactorings and the check was not performed which led to broken scripts using this returned value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferret v0.8</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.8/</guid>
      <description>Hooray, Ferret v0.8 has been released!
It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since the last release, but we worked hard to bring new and better Ferret. This release has many new exciting features, but unfortunately, there are also some breaking changes.
You can find the full changelog here.
Let&amp;rsquo;s go!
What&amp;rsquo;s added iframe Ferret finally supports iframe elements. When a page gets loaded, Ferret finds all available elements and provieds an access to them via the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say &#39;Hello&#39; to Ferret</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/say-hello-to-ferret/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/say-hello-to-ferret/</guid>
      <description>As a developer, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably created a couple of web scrapers to get some data from the Internet during your career. That data could be images for an AI project or hotel prices from booking websites for a new travel mobile app or something else. But something that needs data.
It&amp;rsquo;s a relatively easy task to write one or two web scrapers if the amount of required data is small. But it&amp;rsquo;s a completely different level of complexity when you need to scrape big amount of data and, moreover, do it frequently.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
