<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Ferret</title>
    <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Ferret</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.montferret.dev/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferret v0.10.0</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.10.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.10.0/</guid>
      <description>Hello fellow miners, Ferret v0.10.0 has been finally released!
It&amp;rsquo;s been long and busy 6 months since the last release and many of you might thought that the project got abandoned. We assure you it&amp;rsquo;s not! But sometimes life happens and slows you down.
But we are back and ready to rock!
This release has many great features and improvements thank to all our contributors. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the most important ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferret v0.9</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.9/</guid>
      <description>Hello fellow miners, Ferret v0.9 has been released!
In this release, we mostly focused on bug fixes and filling gaps in user interaction functionality.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see what we&amp;rsquo;ve got.
What&amp;rsquo;s added Clearing input values Since early versions, Ferret has INPUT HTML function that allowed to type any value to input HTML element. This works by appending the function parameter to any pre-existing &amp;lt;input&amp;gt; value. While it works fine in many cases, there are some scenarios when a target input field has a preset value which needs to be erased.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferret v0.8.2</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.8.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.8.2/</guid>
      <description>Another portion of hot fixes has arrived!
v0.8.2 release brings some critical fixes.
Scrolling position is not centered In 0.8, we introduced a new behavior for all user interactions. Before any actions like clicking ot typing, we scroll into a target element making it visible in a viewport. But the logic behind it, positioned elements on the top of the viewport, which led to some issues on some websites due to their markup - the elements were still invisible because they were under other elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferret v0.8.1</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.8.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.8.1/</guid>
      <description>With all big features, come small bugs. :)
With this new v0.8.1 release we are providing hot fixes for some of these small ones.
Broken CLICK function In 0.7 CLICK and CLICK_ALL functions were doing a check before clicking and was returning a boolean value indicating whether a target element was clicked. In 0.8 this logic got broken due to internal refactorings and the check was not performed which led to broken scripts using this returned value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferret v0.8</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/ferret-v0.8/</guid>
      <description>Hooray, Ferret v0.8 has been released!
It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since the last release, but we worked hard to bring new and better Ferret. This release has many new exciting features, but unfortunately, there are also some breaking changes.
You can find the full changelog here.
Let&amp;rsquo;s go!
What&amp;rsquo;s added iframe Ferret finally supports iframe elements. When a page gets loaded, Ferret finds all available elements and provieds an access to them via the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say &#39;Hello&#39; to Ferret</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/say-hello-to-ferret/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/blog/say-hello-to-ferret/</guid>
      <description>As a developer, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably created a couple of web scrapers to get some data from the Internet during your career. That data could be images for an AI project or hotel prices from booking websites for a new travel mobile app or something else. But something that needs data.
It&amp;rsquo;s a relatively easy task to write one or two web scrapers if the amount of required data is small. But it&amp;rsquo;s a completely different level of complexity when you need to scrape big amount of data and, moreover, do it frequently.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>