<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General on Ferret</title>
    <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General on Ferret</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.montferret.dev/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/introduction/</guid>
      <description>What is Ferret? Ferret project is an ambitious initiative trying to bring the universal platform for writing scrapers without any hassle. It aims to simplify data extraction from the web for UI testing, machine learning, analytics and more.
Ferret allows you to focus on the data by abstracting away the technical details and complexity of underlying technologies using its own declarative language.
Ferret is extremely portable, extensible and fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/installation/</guid>
      <description>Installation Even though, Ferret comes as a CLI executable, it also can be used as a library.
CLI From binary You can download latest binaries from here.
From the source $ go get github.com/MontFerret/ferret   Library $ go get github.com/MontFerret/ferret/pkg/compiler   Environment In order to use all Ferret features, you will need to have Chrome either installed locally or running in Docker. For ease of use we recommend to run Chrome inside a Docker container:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started</title>
      <link>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.montferret.dev/docs/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Quick start Browserless mode If you want to play with FQL and check its syntax, you can run CLI with the following commands to run Ferret CLI in REPL mode:
$ ferret   Welcome to Ferret REPL Please use `Ctrl-D` to exit this program. % LET doc = DOCUMENT(&#39;https://news.ycombinator.com/&#39;) FOR post IN ELEMENTS(doc, &#39;.storylink&#39;) RETURN post.attributes.href %   NOTE: symbol % is used to start and end multi-line queries.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>